Guide to the Sue Dauphin Houston Area Performing Arts Collection 1985-003
University of Houston Libraries Special Collections
Sue Dauphin Houston Area Performing Arts Collection
1947-1987
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
University of Houston Libraries
1985-003
12.0 Linear Feet
The Sue Dauphin Houston Area Performing Arts Collection consists of eleven boxes of materials dating from 1947 to 1987.
Biographical Information
Born in 1928, Sue Dauphin graduated cum laude from the University of Houston, and earned a Master of Arts in Theatre from the University of Houston Clear Lake. Her syndicated newspaper columns Houston Fine Arts, Diversions, and Curtain Call appeared in a variety of Houston area newspapers. In the course of writing her columns, she became intimately familiar with the many small theatres in the greater Houston area as well as the major professional theatre arts organizations around the world. Ms. Dauphin was the theatre critic for radio station KUHF, where her reviews were heard weekly on the program Curtain Call. In 1981, she authored the book Houston By Stages: A History of Theatre in Houston. She received various national awards in theatre criticism, and also taught theatre classes at Rice University.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was donated to the University of Houston in 1985.
Scope and Contents
The Sue Dauphin Houston Area Performing Arts Collection consists of eleven boxes of materials dating from 1947 to 1987. The collection is made up of three series: Houston Area Performing Arts Venues/Groups, Other Performing Arts Venues/Groups, and Sue Dauphin's Papers. Programs from Houston area theatre companies comprise the bulk of the material. Of particular interest is the breadth of coverage from the smallest groups to major arts organizations. A smaller amount of material represents art exhibitions, her correspondence, and newspaper/radio reviews.
Correspondence; Playbills; Programs (documents); University of Houston -- Alumni and alumnae
- Houston Area Performing Arts Venues/Groups
  - Actor's Place
    - Theatre Materials, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Actor's Workshop
    - Theatre Materials, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - A.D. Players
    - Theatre Materials, 1980-1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Allen and Dorward News
    - Theatre Materials, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alley Theatre
    - Alley News, 1979-1987 (Box 1, Folder 5-9)
    - Death of Nina Vance, February 18, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Interview with Iris Siff, May 29, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Programs - Performing Arts Magazine, 1978-1987 (Box 1, Folder 14-21)
    - Programs - Playbills, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Programs - Alley Theatre Magazine, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Programs - Houston On Stage, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 24-26)
    - Publications, 1979-1986 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Tribute to Iris Siff, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Alvin Community College
    - Theatre Materials, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - American Federation of Television and Radio Artists Screen Actors Guild
    - Theatre Materials, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Arts for Everyone, Inc.
    - Theatre Materials, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Balinese Dinner Theatre
    - Theatre Materials, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Baytown Little Theatre
    - Theatre Materials, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Broadway Spotlight Series
    - Theatre Materials, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Broadway Star Series
    - Theatre Materials, 1982-1988 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Cabaret Theatre, Inc.
    - Theatre Materials, 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Cabaret West
    - Theatre Materials, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Cameo Theatre Arts, Inc.
    - Theatre Materials, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Carillon Arts Center
    - Theatre Materials, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Channing Players, Inc.
    - Theatre Materials, 1980-1983 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Children's Theatre
    - Theatre Materials, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Chocolate Bayou Theatre Company
    - Publications, 1979-1986 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Press Releases, 1979-1987 (Box 2, Folder 13-15)
    - Programs - Tonight!, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 16-17)
    - Programs - Houston Arts Magazine, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Programs - Houston on Stage, 1982-1985 (Box 2, Folder 19-20)
    - Programs - Chocolate Bayou, 1984-1987 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Chocolatier Newsletter, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Christopher Woods/Actor's Theatre, Pandamonium Players
    - Theatre Materials, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Clear Creek Country Theatre
    - Publications, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence, 1982-1986 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Follow Spot Newsletter, 1980-1986 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Press Releases, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Programs, 1965-1982 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - College of the Mainland Community Theatre
    - Publications, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Front Row [Newsletter], 1979-1987 (Box 2, Folder 31-32)
    - Press Releases, 1975-1987 (Box 2, Folder 33-36)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Programs - Houston Arts Magazine, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Programs - Tonight!, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Programs - Callboard Magazine, 1983-1986 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Comedy Workshop
    - Publications, 1980-1987 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Press Releases, 1975-1987 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Press Releases, 1977-1987 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Programs, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Company Onstage
    - Newsletters, 1980-1987 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Photographs, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Programs, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Country Playhouse
    - Publications, 1979-1987 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Manuscripts, 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Newsletters, 1980-1987 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Programs - Country Playhouse Programs, 1980-1987 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Programs - Houston Arts Magazine, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Programs - Houston On Stage, 1983-1985 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Programs - Tonight!, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Dinner Theatre
    - Theatre Materials, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Dramatika Ventures, Inc.
    - Theatre Materials, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - The Ensemble
    - Newsletters, 1981-1987 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Programs - The Ensemble Playbill, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Programs - Tonight!, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Equinox Theatre
    - Publications, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Press Releases, 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Programs, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Galveston County Cultural Arts Council Grand 1894 Opera Houston
    - Publications, 1980-1987 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Press Releases, 1979-1987 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Gilbert & Sullivan Society of Houston
    - Brochures, 1980-1985 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Press Releases, 1963-1983 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Programs - Houston on Stage, 1983-1985 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Programs - Performing Arts Magazine, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Houston Ballet
    - Publications, 1982-1987 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - News Articles, 1982-1986 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Press Releases, 1979-1988 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Programs - Performing Arts Magazine, 1977-1982 (Box 3, Folder 35-39)
    - Programs - Performing Arts Magazine, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Programs - Houston Arts Magazine, 1982-1985 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Programs - Houston on Stage, 1982-1985 (Box 4, Folder 3-5)
    - Reviews, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Houston Community College
    - Theatre Materials, 1985-1987 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Houston Dance Center
    - Theatre Materials, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Houston Festival
    - Theatre Materials, 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Houston Grand Opera
    - Publications, 1982-1988 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Curtain Call, 1979-1982 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Press Releases, 1979-1987 (Box 4, Folder 12-13)
    - Programs - Houston Arts Magazine, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Programs - Houston On Stage, 1983-1985 (Box 4, Folder 15-19)
    - Programs - Opera Curse, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Programs - Performing Arts Magazine, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 21-26)
    - Programs - Performing Arts Magazine, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
    - Silver Anniversary of HGO, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Houston House Theatre
    - Publications, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Programs, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Houston International Theatre School
    - Theatre Materials, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Houston Little Theatre
    - Theatre Materials, 1945-1950 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Houston Lyric Theatre
    - Theatre Materials, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Houston Motion Picture Council
    - Theatre Materials, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Houston Outreach Theatre, Inc.
    - Press Releases, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Houston Playrights' Theatre
    - Theatre Materials, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Houston Pops Orchestra
    - Theatre Materials, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Houston Shakespeare Festival
    - Theatre Materials, 1980-1985 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Houston Studios
    - Theatre Materials, 1979-1988 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - JSC Dinner Theatre
    - Theatre Materials, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Jewish Community Theatre of Houston
    - Press Releases, 1980-1986 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Programs, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Jones Hall
    - Programs, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Kuumba House Repertory Theatre
    - Publications, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Press Releases, 1985-1988 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Programs, 1985-1987 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Limelight Theatre
    - Publications, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Programs, undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Lone Star Historical Drama Association
    - Press Releases, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Programs, 1980-1984 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Publications, 1980-1984 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Macebra Theatre
    - Theatre Materials, undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Main Street Theatre
    - Publications, 1979-1987 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - News Releases, 1979-1987 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Programs, 1982-1987 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Marietta's Dinner Theatre
    - Theatre Materials, undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - MTGH
    - Theatre Materials, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Midtown Art Center
    - Press Releases, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Publications, undated (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Miss Toodle-oo
    - Theatre Materials, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Music Hall
    - Programs/Playbills, 1982-1985 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Publications, 1979-1987 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Musical Theatre Guild of Houston
    - Press Releases, 1979-1987 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Publications, 1976-1987 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Nipper's Number "1" Plays and Players
    - Theatre Materials, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - North Harris County College
    - Theatre Materials, 1985-1987 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Pasadena Little Theatre
    - Publications, 1964-1987 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Press Releases, 1979-1987 (Box 5, Folder 45-46)
    - Programs, 1979-1986 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Plays for Living
    - Theatre Materials, 1966-1983 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Radio Music Theatre
    - Press Releases, 1985-1987 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Publications, 1984-1987 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Red Windmill Theatre
    - Press Releases, 1979-1983 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Programs, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Publications, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Rice Players
    - Programs, 1981-1984 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Publications, 1981-1986 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Rockefeller's Night Club
    - Theatre Materials, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Skeleton Productions
    - Theatre Materials, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Society for the Performing Arts
    - Press Releases, 1979-1987 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Programs - Performing Arts Magazine, 1971-1986 (Box 6, Folder 9-18)
    - Programs - Houston Arts Magazine, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Programs - Houston on Stage, 1983-1985 (Box 6, Folder 20-22)
    - Programs - Performing Arts, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Publications, 1969-1982 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Southern Star Amphitheatre
    - Photographs, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Press Releases, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Publications, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Spellbinders Comedy Club
    - Theatre Materials, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Stages
    - Photographs, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Publications, 1978-1986 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Reviews, 1979-1982 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Press Releases, 1979-1987 (Box 7, Folder 5-7)
    - Stages News, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Programs - Tonight!, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 9-10)
    - Programs - Houston Arts Magazine, 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Programs - Houston on Stage, 1982-1985 (Box 7, Folder 12-14)
    - Programs - Stages' Programs, 1986-1987 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Strand Street Theatre
    - Press Releases, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Programs, 1982-1984 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Publications, 1980-1985 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - TTI Theatrical Productions
    - Press Releases, 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Publications, undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Teatro Bilingue de Ripley House
    - Theatre Materials, undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Texas Chamber Orchestra
    - Theatre Materials, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Texas Opera Theatre
    - Theatre Materials, 1979-1981 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Texas Renaissance Festival
    - Public Releases, 1979-1981 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Publications, undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Theatre on Wheels
    - Theatre Materials, 1983-1984 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Theatre Showcase
    - Theatre Materials, undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Theatre Southwest
    - Publications, 1979-1982 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Press Releases, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Programs - Theatre Southwest, 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Programs - Houston Arts Magazine, 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Theatre Suburbia
    - Press Releases, 1979-1987 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Programs - Tonight!, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Programs - Houston Arts Magazine, 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Priograms - Theatre Suburbia, undated (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Photographs, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Publications, 1982-1987 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Theatre Under the Stars
    - Publications, 1979-1987 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Press Releases, 1979-1987 (Box 7, Folder 39-40)
    - Programs - Performing Arts, 1977-1987 (Box 8, Folder 1-6)
    - Programs - Houston Arts, 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Programs - Houston On Stage, 1983-1985 (Box 8, Folder 8-9)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Tower Theatre
    - Publications, 1979-1985 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Programs - Tower Theatre, 1979-1985 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Programs - Playbills, 1983-1985 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - University of Houston at Clear Lake City
    - Publications, 1979-1983 (Box 8, Folder 14-15)
    - Press Releases, 1979-1986 (Box 8, Folder 16-17)
    - Programs, 1974-1984 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - University of Houston Drama Department
    - Publications, 1980-1986 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Press Releases, 1979-1982 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Programs - UH Programs, 1980-1987 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Programs - Houston Arts Magazine, 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - University of St. Thomas Drama Department
    - Publications, 1979-1984 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Programs, 1979-1984 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Upper Deck Theatre, Galveston College
    - Theatre Materials, 1979-1982 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Upstage Dinner Theatre
    - Theatre Materials, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Village Loft Dinner Theatre
    - Theatre Materials, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Way Off Broadway Productions
    - Theatre Materials, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Windmill Dinner Theatre
    - Theatre Materials, undated (Box 9, Folder 5-6)
  - Women in Theatre Network
    - Theatre Materials, 1986-1987 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Wortham Center Information Packet
    - Theatre Materials, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 8-9)
  - Writers Clinic, Inc.
    - Theatre Materials, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Writers in Performance
    - Theatre Materials, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Young Audiences of Houston
    - Theatre Materials, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Other Performing Arts Venues/Groups
  - Texas
    - Dallas Theatre Center - Press Releases, 1979-1984 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - San Antonio Little Theatre (SALT), undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Schulenburg High School Theatre, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - California
    - Publications, 1975-1985 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Programs, 1983-1986 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - New York
    - American Theatre Critics Association, 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Foundation for the Extension and Development of American Professional Theatre, undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Press Releases, 1986-1987 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Publications and Programs, 1979-1987 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Publications and Programs, undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Playbills - Various Theatres, 1979-1987 (Box 9, Folder 23-26)
    - Script Writers News, 1980-1982 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Other States
    - Theatre Materials, 1979-1987 (Box 9, Folder 28-29)
- Sue Dauphin's Papers
  - Art Exhibitions
    - Archway Gallery, 1982-1985 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - College of the Mainland Gallery, 1981-1987 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - E.W. Forbes and Associates, undated (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - The Main Gallery, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Marjorie Kauffman Graphics, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Meredith Long & Company, 1979-1982 (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
    - Molly Smyth-Art Katzen Newsletter, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Publications, 1981-1987 (Box 10, Folder 4-5)
    - Southwest Concerts - Press Releases, 1970-1982 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Southwest Concerts - Programs, 1979-1982 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Southwest Concerts - Publications, 1975-1982 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Rice Museum, 1979-1983 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Speedby's Old Prints, 1980-1985 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Texas A&M University, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - University of Houston Clear Lake, 1979-1982 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - University of Houston Downtown, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - University of Houston, 1980-1987 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - University of Texas at Austin, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Watson/de Nagy & Company, 1979-1987 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Watson/Willour & Company, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Art Exhibit Publications
    - Publications, 1979-1986 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Publications
    - Publications, 1979-1986 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Business Cards
    - Business Cards, undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence
    - Correspondence, 1979-1986 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Cultural Arts Council
    - Calendars and miscellaneous, 1981-1985 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Museum of Fine Arts Houston
    - Photographs, 1976-1986 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Publications, 1979-1987 (Box 10, Folder 24-25)
    - Press Releases, 1981-1987 (Box 10, Folder 26-27)
    - Calendar News, 1984-1987 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Newspaper Clippings
    - Clippings, 1977-1984 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Page mock-up for dust jacket of "Houston by Stages"
    - Mock-up, undated (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Publicity Photographs
    - Photographs, undated (Box 10, Folder 31-32)
  - Resumes
    - Resumes, undated (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Scripts for KUHF "Curtain Call"
    - Scripts, 1979-1987 (Box 11, Folder 1-8)
  - Miscellaneous published reviews
    - 1977-1983 (Box 11, Folder 10-16)
  - "Houston By Stages: A History of Theatre in Houston" by Sue Dauphin
    Scope and Contents
    PN2277.H68xD37
    - Book, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 17)